Akshata Parate

Email id: akshataparate@gmail.com Contact No: 9561963746

Summary:

As I a passionate about UX design and research, I started exploring UX before entering into the professional course which I am currently pursuing. I have learned basic principles of UX design through the projects that I did during the initial phase of learning UX Design. As a motivated professional, I'm constantly striving to improve my techniques, expand my skill set and find new opportunities to grow. Each of my projects has provided me with this growth and allowed me to establish myself within this competitive industry. I believe that traditional values or beliefs are the basis for the evolution of the new modern world.

Skills:

Adobe Illustrator

Adobe XD

Adobe Indesign

Figma

Invision Studio

Wireframing

Prototyping

Interaction Design

Information Design

Work Experience - 1:

Prabal Design | User Experience Design Intern

Jan 2022 - Present

Responsibilities:

In Prabal Design, I work with clients to understand their needs and requirements for their products. As an intern, I work on a complete UX process that includes design research, user analysis, information flow and architecture, wireframing, and mockups.

Work Experience - 2:

Gigsy India | User Experience Design Intern

June 2021 - July 2021

Responsibilities:

In this internship, I worked on the interface and featured on the landing page of the company's site to gain more traffic on that. Similarly, I have created the interface for the analytics page of the user dashboard where all the statistics of users were displayed.

Work Experience - 2:

Atos Syntel Pvt Ltd | Associate Consultant

March 2018 - August 2020

Responsibilities:

I was working as an associate consultant in Atos Syntel Pvt . Ltd. My domain of work was ETL and data warehousing. My key responsibilities were

Communicating with Clients and Understanding user

requirements

Impact Analysis

Applying the transformation rules

Deploying the products to clients

Education:

Masters in Design - Human Centered Design

Srishti Institute of Art, Design and Technology, Bangalore Oct 2020 - May 2022

Post Graduate Diploma in Advanced Computing (C-DAC)

Institute of Advanced Computing and Software Development, Akurdi

Aug 2017 - Feb 2018

Bachlor's of Engineering - Information Technology

St. Vincent Pallotti College of Engineering and Technology,

Nagpur

June 2013 - May 2017

Languages:

English

Hindi

Marathi

Online Profiles:

Behance

https://www.behance.net/akshata20

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/akshataparate/